york.ac.uk 2019-12-19

# Legal statements - About the University, The University of York

## Disclaimer

## Disclaimer

To the extent permitted by law, the University provides this website and its contents on an "as is" basis and makes no representation or warranty of any kind regarding this website or any information, content, products or services on it. The University does not represent or warrant that the information accessible via this website is accurate, complete or current. In no circumstances, to the extent permitted by law, shall the University or or any of its officers or employees be liable for any loss, additional costs or damage (howsoever arising) suffered as a result of any use of this website or its contents.

### Course information

The information on this website relating to study programmes is correct at the time of publishing and every attempt is made to ensure its accuracy.  However, the information is issued for the general guidance of students entering the University and does not form part of any contract. The University aims to provide the courses and facilities described on this website, but reserves the right to withdraw or to make alterations to courses and facilities without notice if necessary. The University always welcomes comments on its courses. However, the University's contracts with its students do not confer benefits on third parties for the purposes of the Contracts (Rights of Third Parties) Act 1999.

### Personal staff and student pages

The University does not monitor personal staff or student pages published independently of their work at the University. The views and information on such pages do not constitute official University information, and need not reflect the views of the institution. The information on personal staff and student pages is not provided by the University. Consequently, the institution does not and cannot guarantee the accuracy of such information. All authors, whether publishing official University information or unofficial personal information, are expected to follow the University's Regulations for the use of computing facilities.

### Links to third party information

This website includes links to third party web sites. These links are used to provide further information and are not intended to signify that the University endorses such websites and/or their content. The University takes no responsibility for any loss or damage suffered as a result of using the information published on any of the pages of the linked web sites.

## Privacy

## Privacy

### Data Protection

The University recognises the importance of personal privacy and ensures that all personal data is held in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation and Data Protection Act 2018. Compliance is managed by the [University's Records Manager](https://www.york.ac.uk/records-management/dp/) in accordance with the [University's DPA policy and procedures](https://www.york.ac.uk/records-management/dp/).

### Freedom of Information Act

The University is committed to the principles of freedom of information. The [University's Publication Scheme](http://www.york.ac.uk/recordsmanagement/foi/) is a guide to the information the University publishes. Compliance is overseen by the [Information Governance Officer](https://www.york.ac.uk/records-management/contact/) in accordance with the [University's FoIA policies and procedures](https://www.york.ac.uk/records-management/foi/).

### Logs

The University maintains logs of its servers’ activities. The server log files include the IP address of each computer which accesses the University’s website. The logs are used to support essential maintenance of the site including analysing how the site is used.

### Web forms

A site visitor may be asked to provide personal information when requesting a service. For example, visitors requesting a printed copy of a prospectus may be asked to complete an online form. By supplying this personal information, the visitor consents to the University storing the information for the stated purpose. The information is held by the University in accordance with the provisions of the General Data Protection Regulation and Data Protection Act 2018. A copy of the University’s General Privacy Notice can be found [here](https://www.york.ac.uk/records-management/dp/your-info/).

For Data Protection Officer contact details see [here](https://www.york.ac.uk/records-management/dp/).

## **Unibuddy Enquirer Privacy Notice**

This privacy notice is for Unibuddy enquirers who are interested in applying to the University of York and Hull York Medical School (HYMS).

It sets out the ways in which the University of York gathers, uses, stores and shares your data. It also sets out how long we keep your data and what rights you have in relation to your data under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

For the purposes of this privacy notice, University of York is the Data Controller as defined in the General Data Protection Regulation. We are registered with the Information Commissioner’s Office and our entry can be found [here](https://ico.org.uk/ESDWebPages/Entry/Z4855807). Our registration number is: Z4855807.   

**Where do we get your data from?**

Data is provided directly by you to the University of York through the Unibuddy app.

**What data do wehave?**

[Personal data](https://www.york.ac.uk/records-management/dp/introduction/#tab-4) including:

  * your first name, country of residence;
  * any information you may choose to disclose to us via the Unibuddy app including; email address, phone number, date of birth, area of academic interest.

[Special category data](https://www.york.ac.uk/records-management/dp/introduction/#tab-4) including information about disability, health, gender identity, ethnicity and racial origin.

**What is our legal basis for processing your data?**

Typically, data will be processed:

  * because you have given us your consent at the point of registration with the Unibuddy app.

**How do we use your data?**

The University may process your personal data for the following purposes:

  * to enable effective communication with you regarding your enquiry;
  * to monitor engagement and enquiry response times;
  * for University staff to measure levels of participant engagement.

**Who do we share your data with?**

Data will be accessed by relevant University of York employees (e.g. admissions team staff) and student ambassadors. In addition, Unibuddy, the 3rd party app provider, will have access to your data. For further information about how Unibuddy uses your data please see, <https://unibuddy.co/terms-and-conditions#Privacy%20Policy>

**How do we keep your data secure?**

The University takes information security extremely seriously and has implemented appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect personal data and special category data. Access to information is restricted on a need-to-know basis and security arrangements are regularly reviewed to ensure their continued suitability. For further information please see, [https://www.york.ac.uk/it-services/](https://www.york.ac.uk/it-services/security/)[security](https://www.york.ac.uk/it-services/security/)[/](https://www.york.ac.uk/it-services/security/).  

In addition, the University has put in place an appropriate contract with Unibuddy to ensure data is handled appropriately and in full compliance with relevant data protection law. For further information on Unibuddy's security arrangements see, <https://unibuddy.co/terms-and-conditions#Privacy%20Policy>.

**How long will we keep your data?**

The University will retain your data in line with legal requirements or where there is a business need. Retention timeframes will be determined in line with the University’s Records Retention Schedule.

**What rights do you have in relation to your data?**

Under the General Data Protection Regulation, you have a right of access to your data, a right to rectification, erasure (in certain circumstances), restriction, objection or portability (in certain circumstances). You also have a right to withdraw consent. If you would like to exercise any of these rights please contact [international@york.ac.uk](mailto:international@york.ac.uk). For all other requests, please see <https://www.york.ac.uk/records-management/dp/individualsrights/>. 

**Questions or concerns**

If you have any questions about this privacy notice or concerns about how your data is being processed, please contact the University’s Data Protection Officer at [dataprotection@york.ac.uk](mailto:dataprotection@york.ac.uk).

**Right to complain**

If you are unhappy with the way in which the University has handled your personal data, you have a right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office. For information on reporting a concern to the Information Commissioner’s Office, please see [www.ico.org.uk/concerns](http://www.ico.org.uk/concerns).
